Joe Aguado

Web Developer

PROJECTS

Bilingual Web Developer with a background in Financial Advisor Services and Business

Administration Management.

I strive to make meaningful, deployable projects that follow

write code and contribute to

industry build standards. I aspire to

projects that others can learn from.

In 2016 I built my first weather API

app using Ruby on Rails. I started

Typescript by making a full-stack

deployed application using the

Next.js framework.

making my first HTML websites in

2004. My short term goal is to learn

Location: North Dallas, Texas Phone: (808) 979-5367

Email: aguado.joe@gmail.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/joe-aguado-3a455311b/

Portfolio: www.joeoverflowcode.github.io/ Github: www.joeoverflowcode.github.io/

Aora / In Progress - Full Stack Video Sharing App

Tech: React Native, Native Wind, Appwrite

Repository: https://github.com/joeoverflowcode/aora

Promptopia / April 2024 - Full Stack create/read/update/destroy App **Tech:** Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Google OAuth, Mongoose, MongoDB, Vercel

Live:https://deploy-vercel-promptopia.vercel.app/

Repository: https://github.com/ioeoverflowcode/deploy_vercel_promptopia

Texas Coding Club / March 2024 - Front-End Deployed Blog

Tech: React, Tailwind CSS, Figma, Canva, DreamHost

Live:www.texascodingclub.com

Repository: https://github.com/XINEXPORT/vite-ghpages

Bio Behavioral Institute / February 2024 - Front-End MVP Landing

Tech: React, Tailwind, Canva, DreamHost

Live: www.porterprotokeg.com

Repository: https://github.com/joeoverflowcode/bio_behavioral_institute

SKILLS

Most of my recent experience is around the React.js Library and Frameworks. My short term goal is learn and implement Typescript in a full stack project

Languages: Javascript, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Next.js, React Native, Express, Bootstrap

Database: MongoDB, Appwrite, PostgreSQL

Software: Git, Github, Excel, Microsoft Office, Ximple, Bloomberg Terminal, Slack

Deployment: Github Pages, DreamHost, Vercel

Education

My long-term education goal is to continue learning technology until I am able to create meaningful Economic data applications.

DevMountain / Software Engineering

August 2023 - November 2023 Dallas, Texas JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, Express, Postgresql

University of North Texas / Bachelor of Science in Economics

August 2004 - December 2008 Denton, Texas

Magna Cum Laude, 3x Dean's List /Econometrics, Statistics, Calculus I & II

PRIOR EXPERIENCE

Before Technology, I worked 10+ years in Financial Services and followed by 4 years in Business Administration Management.

Ultra Packaging - Bilingual Assistant Operations Manager

September 2019 - September 2023 Dallas, Texas

Scottrade - Financial Advisor Representative

January 2009 - March 2018, St.Louis, Denver, Los Angeles

Mentorship

University of North Texas Economics Department / Mentee

Improved 4 Order to Cash, Key Performance Indicators within a 12 month period. Coordinated with the Accounting department to eliminate 100% of outstanding debt payments for top grossing customers. Integrated a new accounts receivable model which led to an 14% improvement to cash flow.
Relocated with the company 3 times to take on various broker, consultant and advisor roles over 9+ years of service. Took part in training new employees, interviews, and auditing satellite offices. Part of the merger and acquisition staff when Scottrade integrated with TD Ameritrade. Consistently met quarterly brokerage expectations and individual advisor objectives set by firm and regional managers.
Helped launch the mentorship pilot program along with 22 other members of the University of North Texas Department of Economics Alumni Association. I am currently participating and being mentored by a fellow UNT alumn.